Sadegh Bashiri

Java Back-End Developer

Summary

Backend Developer with more than 6 years of practical experience in PHP language implementing range of business logics from E-commerce to job posting websites and others Have worked in agile environments with teammates from 5 to 15 people. led re- architecture of key platform to increase over 60 percent of requests per second in latest position. Have optimized and refactored code base from scratch to increase 45 performance boost in Irantalent project.

Experience



Java Backend Developer

Tamin (ICT & Management Consultancy) - Full-time

Jan 2021 - Present · 2 yrs 5 mos · Tehran Province, Iran

- Engineered features based on business needs (in a team of 10, scrum based).
- Analyzed the project for migrating from monolith to microservice architecture (step one using CQRS, step two using event sourcing).
- Overhauled the legacy code which was in 3 different projects in the company.
- Coached (mentored, pair programing) 2 new comes for better onboarding process for over 1 month.



Java Backend Developer

Maktab Sharif - Full-time

Aug 2020 - Jan 2021 · 6 mos · Tehran Province, Iran

Missions:

- Co-authored with 3 of co-workers to establish backend conventions, principles, and
- Managed cross-functional teams in self-principle manners (by creating more than 10 tech documents).
- Drafted a productive communication with frontend developers from conception to completion (more than 10 knowledge sessions).
- Designed data storage solutions according to project's needs (database design in both RDBMS and key-value databases like Redis).
- Collaborated with business and sales team to better design products bases on clients needs (10 sessions - by-weekly).
- Drove new and innovative solutions to meet business needs (boost client acquire by 100 by the end of year).
- Facilitated developing and maintaining applications with monitoring tools such as telescope, sentry and writing unit tests on every 2 projects.
- Co-authored new technological solutions and implemented to resolve specific client requests.



Software Technical Support Expert

ArianSystem - Full-time

Jul 2019 - Mar 2020 · 9 mos · Tehran Province, Iran

Missions:

- Managed implementing reusable code and libraries for future use (have published 2 packages in Github). principles, and patterns.
- Optimized the application for maximum speed and scalability with well-known tools available.
- Troubleshooted and solved complex problems to boost almost 15 percent performance of the system.
- Executed about 5 unit test knowledge sessions to better awareness of others teammates.

Contact



O Tehran Province, Iran



+989364665266



Sadegh.Bashiri.dev@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/sadeqh-bashiri



github.com/SadeghBashiri

Education

Islamic Azad University of Kermanshah

Bachelor's degree, Computer Software Engineering

Sep 2010 - Oct 2014

skills

- Java Core
- Java EE
- Spring (MVC, Boot, Security, Data, etc)
- Hibernate
- MySQL
- Angular
- Git
- **REST APIs**
- Swagger

AWARDS

- **EMPLOYEE OF THE MONTH**
- LEADERSHIP AWARD
- **BEST PERFORMER AWARD**

Counselled product managers, editorial and business partners to understand software requirements.



Software Technical Support Expert

ShahreNovin - Full-time

Jan 2018 - Aug 2019 · 1 yr 8 mos · Tehran Province, Iran

Missions:

- Use and mandate best practices in software development, including MVC pattern.
- RESTful Web Services and implementing Microservice for all 2 projects.
- Dockerized products for application to run in any infrastructure, quickly and reliably and securely.
- Developed event organizers dashboard with Laravel Launched an online e-shop with OpenCart Developed a Telegram bot improve CRM.
- Influnced in a Cross-functional team of 4 to R&D the new platform.



Software Technical Support Expert

Faratahlilgaran Varjavand - Full-time

Sep 2015 - Jan 2018 · 2 yrs 5 mos · Tehran Province, Iran

Missions:

- Maintenance and support of web-based and Desktop software systems with the Microsoft SQL Server 2008 R2 .
- Create workflows and forms for Customers using BPMS(Business Process Management System).